Lowell Thomas Film Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 19. Home Movies, 1936-1966; 67 cans
  - Bermuda- best reel; Bermuda- worst; Personal Outdoor Gathering; Hawaii 45 [Flying?] Tigers China 45; Around the Fair with Burton Holmes; L.S. Field Day; L.S. & K.G. Field Day; L.S. Field Day 1936; N.E. [New England?] paper chase, Boze's Pups; Queen Mary, 707 linear feet 1 1200ft (16mm) (Can 1444
    Film started off with a man and a little boy running on the beach. The film showed a woman and a dog, then it showed a boat with people in it. The film showed someone catching a fish and then it showed two little boys swimming. It also showed them trying to pull up a weird looking boat on a dock and then it showed them paddling the boat. The film cuts to people riding bicycles and then it showed a boy standing on his head and another boy had kicked him so he can lose his balance, The film also showed them playing golf and then it showed them running and diving in water. The film showed different boats sailing and it showed different buildings. The film showed cars driving by while men in uniforms are walking into a building. The film showed children and elderly people sitting down. Some of the children were participating in events that you would see in track and field events like running, bar jumping and long jumps. The film also showed men, women and children riding horses and it also showed baby dogs.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Black & White; Audio:; Type: Positive
  - Quaker Hill, 645 linear feet 1 1200ft (16mm) (Can 1445)
    "Quaker Hill or The Simple Life". Narrated by Lowell Thomas. This film explores the people and places of Quaker Hill, New York, including Lowell Thomas, Lowell Thomas, Jr., and Fran Thomas.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio: Optical; Type: Positive
  - 17th Annual Horse Show 1957, 550 linear feet 1 1200ft (16mm) (Can 1446)
    "Annual Horse Show", "Quaker Hill and Timber trails to the Lowell Thomas Stables". People riding horses in formations. A polo match. Ribbons and trophies are being handed out. People hanging out by a lake. Children playing games, relay races, scavenger hunts, and canoe races. A group playing baseball and field games.; Format: 16mm; Picture: Color; Audio:; Type: Positive